A Guide to the Christopher Newport College, President's correspondence and subject files, 1962-1976
Library of Virginia
Library of Virginia
Christopher Newport College, President's correspondence and subject files, 1962-1976
The Library of Virginia
30747
10 cu. ft., 10 boxes
Christopher Newport College
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
There are no restrictions.
Acquisition Information
Collection transferred 19 December 1979.
Historical Information
Founded in 1960 as Christopher Newport College, the academic institution was a two-year branch of the College of William and Mary located in the city of Newport News, Virginia. Christopher Newport gained independence in 1977 and became the Christopher Newport University in 1992.
Biographical Information
Hughes Westcott Cunningham was Christopher Newport College's first director and later served as the college's first president from 1961-1970.
Psychology professor and dean of students, Dr. James C. Windsor, became president in 1970. Windsor established the student counseling center, which was renamed in his honor in 2012. Windsor served as president from 1970-1979.
Scope and Content
This collection contains memorandum, reports, correspondence and board minutes concerning the administration and operation of Christopher Newport College, 1962-1976.
Arrangement
This collection is arranged with respect to the original order in which the collection was received. Some boxes and folders may overlap in date ranges.
Contents List
- Correspondence and memorandum, 1974 September-November, 1976 (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Correspondence and memorandum, 1974 November-1975 February (Box 1, Folder 2)
- Correspondence, minutes, and memorandum, 1974 September-October (Box 1, Folder 3)
- Correspondence, reports, minutes, and memorandum, 1974 July-September (Box 1, Folder 4)
- Correspondence, reports, minutes, and memorandum, 1974 February-May (Box 1, Folder 5)
- Correspondence, reports, minutes, and memorandum, 1974 June-September (Box 1, Folder 6)
- Correspondence, reports, minutes, and memorandum, 1974 April-June (Box 1, Folder 7)
- Correspondence, reports, minutes, and memorandum, 1974 February-April (Box 1, Folder 8)
- Correspondence, reports, minutes, and memorandum, 1974 February-March (Box 1, Folder 9)
- Correspondence, reports, minutes, and memorandum, 1974 January-February (Box 2, Folder 1)
- Correspondence, reports, minutes, and memorandum, 1974 January (Box 2, Folder 2)
- Correspondence, reports, minutes, and memorandum, 1974 January (Box 2, Folder 3)
- Correspondence, reports, minutes, and memorandum, 1973 December-1974 January (Box 2, Folder 4)
- Correspondence, reports, minutes, and memorandum, 1973 November-December (Box 2, Folder 5)
- Correspondence, reports, minutes, and memorandum, 1973 October-November (Box 2, Folder 6)
- Correspondence, reports, minutes, and memorandum, 1973 August-September (Box 2, Folder 7)
- Correspondence, reports, minutes, and memorandum, 1973 August-October (Box 2, Folder 8)
- Correspondence, reports, minutes, and memorandum, 1973 June-August (Box 2, Folder 9)
- Correspondence, reports, minutes, and memorandum, 1973 April-July (Box 2, Folder 10)
- Correspondence, reports, minutes, and memorandum, 1973 March-June (Box 2, Folder 11)
- Correspondence, reports, minutes, and memorandum, 1973 April-May (Box 2, Folder 12)
- Correspondence, reports, minutes, and memorandum, 1973 March-April (Box 2, Folder 13)
- Correspondence, reports, minutes, and memorandum, 1973 March-May (Box 2, Folder 14)
- Correspondence, reports, minutes, and memorandum, 1973 February-March (Box 2, Folder 15)
- Correspondence, reports, minutes, and memorandum, 1973 January-February (Box 3, Folder 1)
- Correspondence, reports, minutes, and memorandum, 1973 January (Box 3, Folder 2)
- Correspondence, reports, minutes, and memorandum, 1972 October-November (Box 3, Folder 3)
- Correspondence, reports, minutes, and memorandum, 1972 August-October (Box 3, Folder 4)
- Correspondence, reports, minutes, and memorandum, 1972 August-September (Box 3, Folder 5)
- Correspondence, reports, minutes, and memorandum, 1972 July-October (Box 3, Folder 6)
- Correspondence, reports, minutes, and memorandum, 1972 September (Box 3, Folder 7)
- Correspondence, reports, minutes, and memorandum, 1972 August-September (Box 3, Folder 8)
- Correspondence, reports, minutes, and memorandum, 1972 July-August (Box 3, Folder 9)
- Correspondence, reports, minutes, and memorandum, 1972 May-July (Box 3, Folder 10)
- Correspondence, reports, minutes, and memorandum, 1972 June (Box 3, Folder 11)
- Correspondence, reports, minutes, and memorandum, 1972 May-June (Box 3, Folder 12)
- Correspondence, reports, minutes, and memorandum, 1972 May (Box 3, Folder 13)
- Correspondence, reports, minutes, and memorandum, 1972 April (Box 3, Folder 14)
- Correspondence, reports, minutes, and memorandum, 1972 March-April (Box 3, Folder 15)
- Correspondence, reports, minutes, and memorandum, 1972 March (Box 3, Folder 16)
- Correspondence, reports, minutes, and memorandum, 1972 March (Box 3, Folder 17)
- Correspondence, reports, minutes, and memorandum, 1972 January-March (Box 3, Folder 18)
- Academic Advising Information, Christopher Newport University, 1970 September (Box 3, Folder 19)
- Christopher Newport College of the College of William and Mary, Capital Outlay Requests, 1966-1972 (Box 4, Folder 1)
- Christopher Newport College of the College of William and Mary, Capital Outlay Requests, 1962-1968 (Box 4, Folder 2)
- Budget Exhibit for Christopher Newport College of the College of William and Mary, 1970-1972 (Box 4, Folder 3)
- Budget Exhibit, Christopher Newport College of the College of William and Mary, 1972-1974 (Box 4, Folder 4)
- Budget Exhibit, Christopher Newport College of the College of William and Mary, 1972-1974 (Box 4, Folder 5)
- Budget Exhibit, Christopher Newport College of the College of William and Mary, 1972-1974 (Box 4, Folder 6)
- Christopher Newport College of the College of William and Mary, Capital Outlay Projections, 1970-1980, Maintenance and Operation, 1970-1972 (Box 4, Folder 7)
- Christopher Newport College of the College of William and Mary, Capital Outlay Projections for 1970-1980, Maintenance and Operation, 1970-1972 1970-1972 (Box 4, Folder 8)
- Christopher Newport College of the College of William and Mary, By-Laws of the Faculty, circa 1970's (Box 4, Folder 9)
- Christopher Newport College of the College of William and Mary in Virginia, Degree Program Proposals, 1968 November 18 (Box 4, Folder 10)
- Board Materials, Mr. Cunningham, 1963-1966 (Box 4, Folder 11)
- Board Materials, Mr. Cunningham, 1965-1971 (Box 4, Folder 12)
- Board Materials, Mr. Cunningham, 1960-1966 (Box 4, Folder 13)
- Announcements, 1964-1967 (Box 5, Folder 1)
- Announcements, 1967-1969 (Box 5, Folder 2)
- Announcements, 1968-1970 (Box 5, Folder 3)
- Annual Meetings, 1967-1969 (Box 5, Folder 4)
- Announcement of Courses, 1963-1969 (Box 5, Folder 5)
- Mr. Kuhn, Director of the Budget, 1962-1969 (Box 5, Folder 6)
- Day File, 1962 April (Box 5, Folder 7)
- Accreditation, 1962-1963 (Box 5, Folder 8)
- Alumni Association, College of William and Mary, 1966 (Box 5, Folder 9)
- American Council on Education, 1964-1971 (Box 5, Folder 10)
- Articulation Committee, 1969 (Box 5, Folder 11)
- Business Office, 1968-1969 (Box 5, Folder 12)
- Committee on Academic Status, 1963-1969 (Box 5, Folder 13)
- Dedication Ceremonies correspondence, 1965 (Box 5, Folder 14)
- Director, 1958-1963 (Box 5, Folder 15)
- Directories, Copies of School Paper, 1961-1962, 1963-1963 (Box 5, Folder 16)
- Resolution approving use of local funds, 1963 (Box 5, Folder 17)
- Self Study, 1963-1967 (Box 5, Folder 18)
- Quarterly Report Forms, H. Douglas Hamner, 1969 (Box 5, Folder 19)
- Newport News, Mr. H.W. Cunningham, Provost, Christopher Newport College, 1969 (Box 5, Folder 20)
- Parking Lots, 1964-1966 (Box 5, Folder 21)
- Personnel (State Division), 1962-1969 (Box 6, Folder 1)
- Regional Education Labs for the Carolinas and Virginia, 1966 (Box 6, Folder 2)
- Richard Bland College, 1970 (Box 6, Folder 3)
- Riverside Hospital, 1961-1967 (Box 6, Folder 4)
- Salary Scales, 1964-1969 (Box 6, Folder 5)
- SCATS, 1968 (Box 6, Folder 6)
- Scholarships and donations to the College - other than library, 1963-1969 (Box 6, Folder 7)
- Self-Study - Follow-up, 1969 (Box 6, Folder 8)
- Virginia Advisory Legislative Council, 1970 (Box 6, Folder 9)
- Vita for H. Westcott Cunningham, undated (Box 6, Folder 10)
- Memorandum - faculty, 1962-1969 (Box 6, Folder 11)
- Programs, memos, and correspondence, 1967-1968 (Box 6, Folder 12)
- Minutes and memorandums, 1967-1970 (Box 6, Folder 13)
- Reports, memorandums, and correspondence, 1962-1969 (Box 6, Folder 14)
- Degree Program Proposals, 1969 November (Box 6, Folder 15)
- Degree Program Proposals, 1968 November 18 (Box 6, Folder 16)
- Correspondence, 1976 (Box 6, Folder 17)
- Correspondence, 1976 (Box 6, Folder 18)
- Correspondence and memos, 1976 (Box 6, Folder 19)
- Correspondence, June and July, unsorted, 1971 (Box 6, Folder 20)
- Correspondence, 1971 May-June (Box 7, Folder 1)
- Correspondence, 1971 May-September (Box 7, Folder 2)
- Correspondence - Outgoing, 1970 May-1971 January (Box 7, Folder 3)
- Correspondence, 1970 December-1971 February (Box 7, Folder 4)
- Correspondence, 1971 February-May (Box 7, Folder 5)
- Correspondence - Incoming, 1970 July-1971 January (Box 7, Folder 6)
- Budget, capital outlay, 1971 May-September (Box 7, Folder 7)
- Resolutions and other papers, 1970 May-1971 May (Box 7, Folder 8)
- Commencement, 1974-1976 (Box 7, Folder 9)
- Data Management, 1970 (Box 7, Folder 10)
- Capital outlay requests, 1966-1972 (Box 7, Folder 11)
- Memo - Academic Affairs Committee, Board of Visitors, 1969 February-1971 June (Box 7, Folder 12)
- Resolutions, budgets, requests, and other papers, 1972-1975 (Box 8, Folder 1)
- Resolutions, budgets, requests, and other papers, 1971-1975 (Box 8, Folder 2)
- Resolutions, budgets, requests, and other papers, 1967-1975 (Box 8, Folder 3)
- Resolutions, budgets, requests, and other papers, 1963-1974 (Box 8, Folder 4)
- Resolutions, budgets, requests, and other papers, 1969-1974 (Box 8, Folder 5)
- Agenda, memos, correspondence, and other papers, 1975 June-July (Box 8, Folder 6)
- Correspondence, 1975 August-September (Box 8, Folder 7)
- Correspondence, 1975 March-May (Box 8, Folder 8)
- Correspondence and memos, 1975 February-April (Box 8, Folder 9)
- Correspondence and memos, 1975 April-June (Box 8, Folder 10)
- Correspondence and memos, 1976 October-December (Box 9, Folder 1)
- Resignations, correspondence, and other papers, 1975 May-July (Box 9, Folder 2)
- Correspondence and memos, 1975 July-August (Box 9, Folder 3)
- Departmental communications and memos, 1975 January-April (Box 9, Folder 4)
- Correspondence and memos, 1975 April-May (Box 9, Folder 5)
- Correspondence and memos, 1972 November-December 1972 November-December (Box 9, Folder 6)
- Memos, minutes, and departmental communications, 1975 October-December (Box 9, Folder 7)
- Correspondence and memos, 1975 September-October (Box 9, Folder 8)
- Correspondence and memos, 1975 November-1976 February (Box 9, Folder 9)
- Correspondence and memos, 1976 September-October (Box 10, Folder 1)
- Reports, memos, budgets, and capital outlay requests, 1972-1977 (Box 10, Folder 2)
- Correspondence and memos, 1976 July-1977 January (Box 10, Folder 3)
- Correspondence, 1975 October-1976 April (Box 10, Folder 4)